Guide to the Fedor Stepun Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1943-65; Series I; 16; (41 boxes)
  - GENERAL FILES
    - "H" General, 1946-64, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 442-449)
      - _ La pensée russe, 1951-65 (Box 26, Folder 893)
        - Petersen, Mariia, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 897)
        - Pfeiffer, Kurt Pfeiffer, Hannel, 1949-62 (Box 26, Folder 898)
        - Philipps-Universität, 1954-55 (Box 26, Folder 899)
          See also: Ernst Benz
        - Philosophische Gesellschaft Augsburg, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 900)
        - Philosophische-Theologische Hochschule Bamberg, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 901)
        - Piepenstock, Marianne, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 902)
        - Pieper, Josef, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 903)
        - Piper, Klaus, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 904)
          Includes typescripts of untitled essays by FAS and Roman Gul'
      - _ Pirang, A., 1947-63 (Box 26, Folder 905)
        Includes: "Predsedateliu TSentral'nogo Pravleniia Germanskogo Otdela Natsional'no- Trudovogo Soiuza" by A. Pirang; "Predsedateliu sovetov redaktorov radiostantsii "Svoboda" by N. Poltoratskii
        - Piroschkova, Vera, 1952-64, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 906)
          Also spelled: Pirozhkova
        - Plank, Charlotte, 1947-59 (Box 26, Folder 907)
      - _ Plank, Rudolf, 1946-64, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 908)
        - Platen, Alexander von, 1947-56 (Box 26, Folder 909)
        - Plessner, H., 1960-62 (Box 26, Folder 910)
        - Pletnev, R., 1959 (Box 26, Folder 911)
      - _ Poltoratskii, N. P., 1947-64 (Box 26, Folder 912)
        Also spelled: Poltoratzky
        See also: A. Pirang
        - Pomerantsev, K., 1961-62 (Box 26, Folder 913)
        - Porsh, Tat'iana, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 914)
        - Posev, 1945-64 (Box 26, Folder 915)
          Also known as Possev-Verlag
          See also: L. D. Rzhevskii
      - _ Pozov, A., 1962-64 (Box 26, Folder 916)
        - Preuss, G. A. Helmut, 1956-59 (Box 26, Folder 917)
        - Pridik, Heinrich, 1947-48 (Box 26, Folder 918)
      - _ Pulkov, L., 1947-54, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 919)
        - Pütz, Hildegard, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 920)
        - Pyman, Avril, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 921)
        - Quatember. Evangelische Jahresbriefe, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 922)
        - "R" General, 1944-65, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 923-928)
        - Rabanus Gemeinde, 1947-57 (Box 27, Folder 929)
        - Radio Bremen, 1952-56 (Box 27, Folder 930)
        - Radio Liberty, 1953-64 (Box 27, Folder 931)
        - Radio München, 1947-49 (Box 27, Folder 932)
      - _ Radzibor, Irene von, 1955-62 (Box 27, Folder 933)
        - Radziuk, Michael, 1949-63 (Box 27, Folder 934)
        - Rainer, Alfred, 1959-62 (Box 27, Folder 935)
        - Rainer Wunderlich Verlag, 1948-54 (Box 27, Folder 936)
        - Rannit, Aleksis, 1964 May 9 (Box 27, Folder 937)
      - _ Rapp, Evgeniia, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 938)
        - Rassem, M., 1965 (Box 27, Folder 939)
        - Regierung von Oberfranken, 1955-57 (Box 27, Folder 940)
        - Reich, Gudrun, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 941)
        - Reinhard, Julie, 1945-60 (Box 27, Folder 942)
        - Reisert, Franz, 1950-59 (Box 27, Folder 943)
        - Reith, Kurt, 1944-47 (Box 27, Folder 944)
        - Religiöse Bildungsarbeit, 1946-57 (Box 27, Folder 945)
          Includes: H. Breucha
        - Remizov, Aleksei M., 1951-54 (Box 27, Folder 946)
        - Remscheider General Anzeiger, 1956-57 (Box 27, Folder 947)
        - Rennenkampff, Gert von, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 948)
        - Renik, E. V., 1958 (Box 27, Folder 949)
        - Rheinfelder, Hans, 1957-64 (Box 27, Folder 950)
          Includes photographs
        - Rheinischer Merkur, 1950-57 (Box 27, Folder 951)
        - RIAS-Berlin, 1954-62 (Box 27, Folder 952)
        - Rickert, Franz, 1946-64 (Box 27, Folder 953)
        - Robakidze, G., 1955-62 (Box 27, Folder 954)
        - Röder, Siegfried, 1962-65 (Box 27, Folder 955)
        - Roessler, Rudolph, 1942-48 (Box 27, Folder 956)
          Also spelled: Rössler Includes Vita Nova Verlag
      - _ Ropp, G. von der, 1946-64 (Box 27, Folder 957)
        - Ropp, Joachim Baron von der, 1956-64 (Box 27, Folder 958)
        - Ropp, Manfred, 1956-58 (Box 27, Folder 959)
        - Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugene, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 960)
        - Roser, Margarette, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 961)
        - Rösler, Elisabeth, 1947, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 962)
      - _ Rössler, Roman, 1950-63, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 963)
        - Rössler, Walter, 1949-53 (Box 28, Folder 964)
        - Roth, Eugen, 1954-65 (Box 28, Folder 965)
        - Rouvier, Jean, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 966)
        - Rovinskii, Vladimir, 1960-62 (Box 28, Folder 967)
        - R. Piper Verlag, 1946-64 (Box 28, Folder 968)
        - Rüdiger, Michael Rüdiger, Gertrude, 1954-64 (Box 28, Folder 969)
        - Rudol'f, Vladimir Rudol'f, Vera, 1948-50 (Box 28, Folder 970)
        - Ruf, Thomas, 1948-54 (Box 28, Folder 971)
        - Ruhle, Dorothea, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 972)
        - Ruperti, Alexander Ruperti, Madia, 1947-64 (Box 28, Folder 973-974)
        - Ruperti, Elisabeth, 1947-63 (Box 28, Folder 975)
        - Ruperti, F., 1944-49 (Box 28, Folder 976)
        - Russian Children's Welfare Society, 1962-63 (Box 28, Folder 977)
          Includes: A. Drewing
        - Russian Review, 1953-59, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 978)
          Includes: D. von Mohrenschild
        - Russkaia Akademicheskaia Gruppa., 1959, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 979)
          Includes: A. V. Kartashev
        - Russkoe Studencheskoe Khristianskoe Dvizhenie, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 980)
        - Rüster, Paul, 1947-56, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 981)
        - Rustow, Alexander, 1957-61 (Box 28, Folder 982)
          Includes: Aktiongemeinschaft sozialer Marktwirtschaft
        - Rüttenauer, Isabella, 1947 Sep 11 (Box 28, Folder 983)
          Copy of letter to Herr Schaezler
      - _ Rzhevskii, Leonid Denisovich, 1951-63 (Box 28, Folder 984)
        Includes: Posev, Grani
        - "S" General, 1944-64, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 985-1001)
        - Saarländischer Kulturgesellschaft, 1953-55 (Box 30, Folder 1002)
      - _ Saarländischer Rundfunk, 1956-58 (Box 30, Folder 1003)
      - _ Saemisch, Ernst (Box 30, Folder 1004)
        - Saemisch, Chata, 1946-65
          Includes correspondence from Ruth Bauer
      - _ Saemisch, Johanna, 1947-65 (Box 30, Folder 1005)
        - Sakhno, E., 1954-63 (Box 30, Folder 1006)
        - Salzburger Hochschulwocken, 1959-62 (Box 30, Folder 1007)
        - Samoilov, E., 1956 (Box 30, Folder 1008)
        - Sanitätstruppenschule (München), 1959-60 (Box 30, Folder 1009)
        - Satin, Georgii von, 1958-59 (Box 30, Folder 1010)
      - _ Satin, T., 1955-64 (Box 30, Folder 1011)
        - Sauerbeck, Hertha, 1951-64 (Box 30, Folder 1012)
          Also known as: H. Sauerback- Bretscheider
        - Sauerbruch, Jaduscha, 1953-55 (Box 30, Folder 1013)
        - Schaller, Heinrich, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 1014)
      - _ Schaller, Jutta, 1947-62 (Box 30, Folder 1015)
        Includes: Volkshochschule Ulmer
        See also: Club Berufstätiger Frauen
      - Scheib, Manfred, 1953-63 (Box 30, Folder 1016)
      - _ Schelcher, Hilda (Box 30, Folder 1017)
        - Schelcher, Arnulf, 1945-64, n.d.
      - _ Scheller, Ilse, 1949-55 (Box 30, Folder 1018)
        - Schereschewsky, James, 1954-61, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1019)
        - Schieck, Hermann, 1963, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1020)
      - _ Schippel, Inge (nee Biener) (Box 30, Folder 1021-1024)
        - Schippel, Peter, 1946-54
        - Schippel, Peter, 1951, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1025)
        - Schloss, Elman, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 1026)
        - Schmemmann, Alexander, 1963 Jan 1 (Box 31, Folder 1027)
          Also spelled: Shmeman
        - Schmid, Eva, 1956-59 (Box 31, Folder 1028)
        - Schmid, Gertrude Schmid, Hans, 1948-50 (Box 31, Folder 1029)
        - Schmidt-Metzen, Toni, 1948-49 (Box 31, Folder 1030)
      - _ Schmidt, Willi, 1944-56 (Box 31, Folder 1031)
        - Schmitt, Jan Dieter, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 1032)
        - Schneider, Paul, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 1033)
      - _ Scholl, Inge, 1946-53 (Box 31, Folder 1034)
        Includes Ulmer Volkshochschule; Gesellschaft der Freunder der Geschwister Scholl-Stiftung
        - Scholz, Luise, 1948-63 (Box 31, Folder 1035)
        - Schomerus, Hans, 1963-64 (Box 31, Folder 1036)
      - _ "Schöner Wohnen" Diskussionsforum, 1959-63 (Box 31, Folder 1037)
        - Schönfeld, Herbert, 1951-52 (Box 31, Folder 1038)
          Includes: Starnberger Kunstkreis
        - Schöningh, Franz Josef, 1951-60 (Box 31, Folder 1039)
          See also Hochland, Süddeutsche Zeitung
      - _ Schröder, Christel Matthias, 1944-63 (Box 31, Folder 1040)
      - _ Schubert, Gertrude, 1945-63, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1041)
        - Schuh-Krähmer, Käte, 1949-50 (Box 31, Folder 1042)
        - Schulenberg, Dagmar, Grafin von der, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 1043)
          Nee Baronesse von Engelhardt
        - Schultze, Bernhard, 1950-51 (Box 31, Folder 1044)
      - _ Schürer, Elisabeth (nee Weddigen), 1947-64 (Box 31, Folder 1045)
        - Schuster, Hermann, 1952-53 (Box 31, Folder 1046)
      - _ Schütz, Paul (Box 31, Folder 1047)
        - Schütz, Johanna, 1952-64, n.d.
        - Schutze, Fritz, 1947-48 (Box 31, Folder 1048)
      - _ Schweizer Rundschau, 1949-58 (Box 31, Folder 1049)
        Includes Siegfrid Streicher
        - Schweizerisches Institut für Auslandforschung, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 1050)
        - Scientia Presse Dienst, 1948-52 (Box 31, Folder 1051)
        - Segal, Regina, 1960-64 (Box 31, Folder 1052)
        - Segalova, Maria, 1962, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1053)
        - Seggelke, Herbert, 1948-54 (Box 31, Folder 1054)
        - Seidel, Karl, 1963-64 (Box 31, Folder 1055)
      - _ Seidenzahl, Hella, 1950-65 (Box 31, Folder 1056)
        - Sekorina, L., 1956, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1057)
      - _ Sementkovksy-Kurilo, Nicola, 1951-53 (Box 31, Folder 1058)
        - Sengenberger, Kurt, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 1059)
        - Setschkareff, Vsevolod, 1955-56 (Box 31, Folder 1060)
        - Seuberlich, Jekaterina, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 1061)
      - _ S. Fischer Verlag, 1957-60 (Box 31, Folder 1062)
        - Shcherbatov, Sergei, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 1063)
        - Sherekh, IUrii, 1947-48 (Box 32, Folder 1064)
          Pseudonym: George Shevelov
        - Shopen, Edmund, 1949-54 (Box 32, Folder 1065)
      - _ Shor, Ol'ga Aleksandrovna, 1954-64 (Box 32, Folder 1066-1070)
        Pseudonym: Ol'ga Deschartes. Includes untitled typescript by O. Shor and V. Ivanov's "Mysli o poezii": typescript, annotated
        - Shpakovskii, Anotolii Ignat'evich, 1946-49 (Box 32, Folder 1071)
        - Sidorenko, Aleksei, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 1072)
      - _ Siemens und Halske (Box 32, Folder 1073)
        - Aktiongesellschaft, 1954-64
      - _ Signorelli, Olga Resnevic, 1945-62 (Box 32, Folder 1074)
      - _ Simundt, Egon Christian (Box 32, Folder 1075-1076)
        - Simundt, Anna Maria, 1959-64
      - _ Sintenis, Tusi, 1958-64 (Box 32, Folder 1077)
        - Sleptsova, O., 1947-59 (Box 32, Folder 1078)
        - Slonim, M., 1944-60 (Box 32, Folder 1079)
      - _ Société internationale pour les (Box 32, Folder 1080)
        - études comparées de civilisations, 1960-61
        - Solov'ev, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1961 Sep 16 (Box 32, Folder 1081)
      - _ Sombart, Corina Nikolaevna, 1948-64 (Box 32, Folder 1082)
        - Sombart, Nikolaus, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 1083)
          Printed pamphlet, inscribed
      - _ Sommer, E., 1949-62 (Box 32, Folder 1084)
        - Sonntagsblatt für die evangelisch- Lutherische Kirche in Bayern, 1948-53 (Box 32, Folder 1085)
      - _ Sorgenfrey, A., 1949-51 (Box 32, Folder 1086)
      - _ Sörup, Richard (Box 32, Folder 1087)
        - Sörup, Erika, 1953-64, n.d.
        - Sovetskii komitet po kul'turnym sviaziam s sootechestvennikami za rubezhom, 1963-64 (Box 32, Folder 1088)
          Includes correspondence from: Vasilii Ivanovich Kirillov
        - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands, 1948-51 (Box 32, Folder 1089)
      - _ Specht, Karl Gustav, 1950-54 (Box 32, Folder 1090)
        - Der Spiegel. Das Deutsche Nachrichten Magazin, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 1091)
      - _ Spies, Sofia (Box 32, Folder 1092-1094)
        - Spies, Rudolf, 1946-58
          Also spelled: Shpis
        - Spies, Vera Spies, Erwin Spies, Rudolf, 1946-62, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1095)
        - Spoerl, Heinrich, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 1096)
        - Sretschinsky, G., 1962 (Box 32, Folder 1097)
          Includes clipping
        - Staatliche Landesbildstelle Hamburg, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 1098)
        - Staatssekretariat für das Französish besetzte Gebiet Württembergs und Hohenzollerns, 1947-48 (Box 33, Folder 1099)
        - Stadelmayer, Franz, 1959-64 (Box 33, Folder 1100)
        - Stadtbucherei Heilbronn, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 1101)
        - Städtische Volkhochschule Nürnberg, 1947-48 (Box 33, Folder 1102)
      - _ Stammler, Heinrich (Box 33, Folder 1103)
        - Stammler, Ursula, 1947-63, n.d.
          Also known as: Andrei Shtammler
        - Starnberger Kunstkreis, 1954-64 (Box 33, Folder 1104)
          See also: Herbert Schönfeld
      - _ Stauder, K. Heinz, 1946-64 (Box 33, Folder 1105)
        - Staufen-Verlag, 1947-48 (Box 33, Folder 1106)
        - Steffensen, Steffen, 1963-64 (Box 33, Folder 1107)
        - Steinwand, H., 1949 (Box 33, Folder 1108)
        - Stellzig, Marie, 1944-48 (Box 33, Folder 1109)
        - Steppuhn, Gertrude, 1951-61 (Box 33, Folder 1110)
        - Steppuhn, Helene, 1942-64 (Box 33, Folder 1111)
      - _ Stepun, Margarita, 1952-63 (Box 33, Folder 1112-1113)
        Includes correspondence from Galina Kuznetsova, clipping
      - _ Stiftsbund, 1949-55 (Box 33, Folder 1114)
        - Stiftung Landerziehungsheim Neubeuern, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 1115)
        - Stiftung Landerziehungsheim Schondorf am Ammersee, Oberbayern, 1953-60 (Box 33, Folder 1116)
        - Stimmen der Zeit, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 1117)
        - Stöcklein, Paul, 1946-52 (Box 33, Folder 1118)
        - Stolberg, Otto, 1949-63 (Box 33, Folder 1119)
          Also known as: Dr. Otto Graf zu Stolberg-Wernigorode
        - Stolzenburg, L., 1955-62 (Box 33, Folder 1120)
        - Strambowski, Anton, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 1121)
        - Strasser, Gerda Strasser, Helwig, 1960-63 (Box 33, Folder 1122)
        - Streitweise, E. Streitweise, F., 1961-63, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1123)
        - Striedter, Jury, 1949 Nov 20 (Box 33, Folder 1124)
        - Strobe, Wolf, 1952-53 (Box 33, Folder 1125)
      - _ Struve, Gleb, 1957-64 (Box 33, Folder 1126)
        - Struve, Nikita A., 1952-61 (Box 33, Folder 1127)
      - _ Strüver, Friedrich, 1950-63 (Box 33, Folder 1128)
      - _ Strüver, Maria (nee Schlecher), 1945-64 (Box 33, Folder 1129-1131)
        - Studentenhilfe München, 1954-57 (Box 33, Folder 1132)
        - Studentenschaft der Universität Heidelberg, 1952-53 (Box 33, Folder 1133)
        - Studentenschaft der Universität Zurich, 1949-51 (Box 33, Folder 1134)
        - Studentenwerk München, 1948-53 (Box 33, Folder 1135)
        - Studentischer Filmclub an der Universität Bonn, 1955-57 (Box 33, Folder 1136)
          Includes: S. Meuschel
        - Studiobühne der Universität Erlangen, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 1137)
        - Stuttgarter Gemeinschaft "Artz und Seelsorger", 1964 (Box 33, Folder 1138)
      - _ Süddeutsche Zeitung, 1948-64 (Box 33, Folder 1139)
        Includes: Franz Josef Schöningh, Walter Panofsky, Hans Joachim Sperr
      - _ Süddeutscher Rundfunk, 1950-59 (Box 33, Folder 1140)
        - Suhrkamp Verlag, 1954-55 (Box 33, Folder 1141)
        - Sukoffsky, Rufina, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 1142)
        - Sulejman, Nadija, 1964-65 (Box 33, Folder 1143)
        - Svoboda. Organ Tsentral'nogo Ob"edineniia Poslevoennykh emigrantov iz SSSR, 1954-57 (Box 33, Folder 1144)
          Includes: IU. Bol'shukhin, F. Lebedev, G. Klimov
        - Szylkarski, W., 1954-55 (Box 33, Folder 1145)
        - "T" General, 1944-65, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1146-1148)
        - Die Tafelrunde, 1953-58 (Box 34, Folder 1149)
        - Tagert, Margot, 1948-64 (Box 34, Folder 1150)
        - Tagesspiegel, 1953-54 (Box 34, Folder 1151)
        - Talhoff, Hildegard, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1152)
      - _ Tarasova, N., 1956-63, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1153)
        Includes correspondence from Grani
      - _ Taube, Otto, 1945-64, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1154)
        - Tesche, Gertrude, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 1155)
        - Teupel, Kurt, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 1156)
        - Theater am Gardenplatz, 1962-63 (Box 34, Folder 1157)
          Also known as Bayerische Staatstheater
        - Theater für Vorarlberg, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 1158)
        - Theatergemeinde. Volksbund für Theater Musik Literatur (München), 1952-59 (Box 34, Folder 1159)
        - Thiel, Erich, 1951-63 (Box 34, Folder 1160)
        - Thuerheim, J. E., 1952 (Box 34, Folder 1161)
        - Tierärztliche Hochschule. Physiologisches Institut, 1957-59 (Box 34, Folder 1162)
      - _ Tillich, Paul (Box 34, Folder 1163-1164)
        - Tillich, Hanna, 1946-63, n.d.
          Includes correspondence from M. Hausner
        - Tolstaia, Lidiia, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 1165)
        - Tometschek, Josef, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 1166)
        - Tomiline, A., 1951-54 (Box 34, Folder 1167)
      - _ Tremmel, N., 1952-65 (Box 34, Folder 1168)
        - Troubetskaia, Sofiia Evgeni'evna, 1962-64 (Box 34, Folder 1169)
      - _ Tschizewskij, D., 1943-64, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1170-1173)
        Also spelled: Chizhevskii, Cyzev'skyj
        - TSentral'noe Obedin'enie Politicheskikh Emigrantov iz SSSR, 1954-58 (Box 34, Folder 1174)
        - Tukankreis, 1959-64 (Box 34, Folder 1175)
        - Tverskoi, Evgenii, 1951 (Box 34, Folder 1176)
        - "U" General, 1947-64, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1177)
        - Ulianov, N., 1953 Dec 5 (Box 35, Folder 1178)
      - _ Ulich, Robert, 1950-62 (Box 35, Folder 1179)
      - _ Ulich, Else, 1956-64, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1180)
        - Ulmer Volkshochschule, 1951-61 (Box 35, Folder 1181)
          Includes: Inge Scholl
          See also: Jutta Schaller
        - Umbach, Rolf, 1953-58 (Box 35, Folder 1182)
        - Una Sancta (München), 1952-53 (Box 35, Folder 1183)
      - _ Universitas, 1946-63; n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1184)
        Includes: S. Maiwald, H. Walter Bahr
        - Universität Erlagen. Seminar für mittlare und neuere Geschichte, 1947-54 (Box 35, Folder 1185)
        - Universität Freiburg, 1953-65 (Box 35, Folder 1186)
          Includes correspondence from Seminar für germanische Philologie
        - Universität Hamburg, 1953-55 (Box 35, Folder 1187)
          Includes: H. Eggers
      - _ Universität Heidelberg, 1952-63 (Box 35, Folder 1188)
        Includes correspondence from Philosophische Fakultät; Slavisches Institut; Studium generale
      - _ Universität Innsbruck, 1957-59 (Box 35, Folder 1189)
      - _ Universität Köln, 1947-64 (Box 35, Folder 1190)
        Includes correspondence from Arbeitsgemeinschaft für Filmfragen; Forschungsinstitut für Soziologie (R. König); Prufungsamt; Soziologisches Seminar (L. Wiese) Wirtschafts und Sozialwissenschaftliche Fakultat
        - Universität Köln. Slavisches Seminar, 1954-62 (Box 35, Folder 1191)
          Includes: R. Olesch
      - _ Universität München, 1946-64 (Box 35, Folder 1192-1194)
        Also known as: Ludwig-Maximilian- Universität (München). Includes correspondence from Chirurgische Klinik (E. Streitweiser); Dekan der Philosophischen Fakultät; Dekanat; Rektorat; Seminar für deutsche Philologie; Sozialferschungsstelle (Brepohl, W.); Soziologisches Institut; Seminar für englishe Philologie; Seminar für slavische Philologie
        - Universität München. Institut für Strafrechtswissenschaften, 1949-64 (Box 35, Folder 1195)
        - Universität München. Philosophisches Seminar, 1956-64 (Box 35, Folder 1196)
        - Universität Tübingen, 1951-57 (Box 35, Folder 1197)
          Includes correspondence from Rechts- und Wirtschafts- Wissenschaftliches Fakultät. Wirtschafter Abteilung; Wirtschaftswissenschaftliches Seminar
        - Unterberger, P. E., 1952-55 (Box 35, Folder 1198)
        - Utzschneider, Leo, 1947-48 (Box 35, Folder 1199)
        - "V" General, 1944-65, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1200-1207)
        - Valentin, F., 1958-62, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1208)
      - _ Van den Bergh, Ellen, 1947-59, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1209)
        - Varshavskii, V., 1957, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1210)
      - _ Vasil'ev, G. (Box 35, Folder 1211)
        - Vasil'ev, X., 1953-61
          Also spelled: Vassiliev
        - Veidle, Vladimir Vasil'evich, 1949-59 (Box 36, Folder 1212)
          Also spelled: W. Weidlé
        - Veit, Otto, 1952-54 (Box 36, Folder 1213)
        - Verband bayerischer Berufsschullehrer (Münich), 1955 (Box 36, Folder 1214)
        - Verband bayerischer Berufsschullehrer. Kreisverband Augesburg, 1960-61 (Box 36, Folder 1215)
        - Verband der deutschen Film-Clubs, 1952-59 (Box 36, Folder 1216)
        - Verband der oberer Angestellter der Eisen- und Stählindustrie, 1951-52 (Box 36, Folder 1217)
        - Verein junger Kaufleute, 1953-54 (Box 36, Folder 1218)
        - Verein von heiligen Karl Borromäus, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 1219)
        - Vereinigte Glanzstoff Fabriken, 1951-52 (Box 36, Folder 1220)
        - Vereinigung der Arbeitgeberverbände, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 1221)
        - Vereinigung Ehemaliger Schülerinnen der Städtischen Riemerschmid- Handelsschule (München), 1960 (Box 36, Folder 1222)
      - _ Vereno, Matthias (Box 36, Folder 1223)
        - Vereno, Gertrude Maria, 1953-57
        - Verlag Anton Pustet, 1960-61 (Box 36, Folder 1224)
        - Verlag der Arche, 1958-59 (Box 36, Folder 1225)
      - _ Verlag Herder Freiburg, 1949-64 (Box 36, Folder 1226)
        - Verlag Kiepenhauer & Witsch, 1953-62 (Box 36, Folder 1227)
        - Verlag Kurt Desch, 1951-63 (Box 36, Folder 1228)
        - Verlag Passavia München-Passau, 1956-57 (Box 36, Folder 1229)
        - Verlag Philipp Reclam Jun. Stuttgart, 1959-64 (Box 36, Folder 1230)
        - Vetter, August, 1951-64 (Box 36, Folder 1231)
      - _ Vietinghoff, Arnold (Box 36, Folder 1232-1233)
        - Vietinghoff, Editha von, 1944-60, n.d.
      - _ Vietinghoff, Erik von (Box 36, Folder 1234-1235)
        - Breithaupt, Inge, 1944-62, n.d.
        - Vietinghoff-Scheel, Egon von, 1946-52 (Box 36, Folder 1236)
        - Vinokurov, Elsa, 1945-63 (Box 36, Folder 1237)
      - _ Vishniak, M. V., 1956-64 (Box 36, Folder 1238)
        - Vittorio Klostermann, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 1239)
        - Vladimirov, Mikhail Nikolaevich, 1947-48 (Box 36, Folder 1240)
        - Volkmann, Hans Erich, 1961-62 (Box 36, Folder 1241)
      - _ Volksbildungskurse Kempten/Allgäu, 1951-61 (Box 36, Folder 1242)
        - Volkshochschule 84 Regensburg, 1963-64 (Box 36, Folder 1243)
        - Volkshochschule Bad-Nauheim, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 1244)
        - Volkshochschule Bamberg, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 1245)
        - Volkshochschule Duisburg, 1961-62 (Box 36, Folder 1246)
        - Volkshochschule Düsseldorf, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 1247)
      - _ Volkshochschule Esslingen, 1946-54 (Box 36, Folder 1248)
        - Volkshochschule Göppingen, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 1249)
        - Volkshochschule Heidelberg, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 1250)
      - _ Volkshochschule Heilbronn, 1947-55 (Box 36, Folder 1251)
        - Volkshochschule Helmstadt, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 1252)
        - Volkshochschule Hildesheim, 1951-54 (Box 36, Folder 1253)
        - Volkshochschule Idar-Oberstein, 1954-56 (Box 36, Folder 1254)
        - Volkshochschule Kassel, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 1255)
        - Volkshochschule Kirchheim-Teck, 1953-56 (Box 36, Folder 1256)
        - Volkshochschule Ludwigschafen, 1950-53 (Box 36, Folder 1257)
      - _ Volkshochschule Miesbach, 1953-58 (Box 36, Folder 1258)
        - Volkshochschule Pforzheim, 1953-54 (Box 36, Folder 1259)
        - Volkshochschule Regensburg, 1952-53 (Box 36, Folder 1260)